Spartacus is a action, drama film directed by Robert Dornhelm.
Sentenced to spend out the rest of his adult life laboring in the harsh deserts of Egypt, the Thracian slave
Spartacus gets a new lease on life when he is purchased by the obese owner of a Roman gladiator school.
Moved by the defiance of an Ethiopian warrior, Draba, Spartacus leads
a slave uprising which threatens Rome's status quo.
As Spartacus gains sympathy within the Roman Senate, he also makes a powerful enemy in form of
Marcus Lucinius Crassus, who makes it a matter of personal honor to crush the rebellion.
Spartacus, played by Goran Višnjić.
Antonius Agrippa, played by Alan Bates.
Marcus Crassus, played by Angus Macfadyen.
Varinia, played by Rhona Mitra.
Lentulus Batiatus, played by Ian McNeice.
David, played by James Frain.
Spartacus is a 2004 North American miniseries directed by Robert Dornhelm and
produced by Ted Kurdyla from a teleplay by Robert Schenkkan.
It aired over two nights on the USA Network, and stars Goran Visnjic, Alan Bates (in his final
television appearance), Angus Macfadyen, Rhona Mitra, Ian McNeice, Ross Kemp and Ben Cross.
It is based on the 1951 novel of the same name by Howard Fast.
The plot, setting, and costumes are nearly identical to those of Stanley Kubrick's 1960 version;
however, this adaptation follows Howard Fast's novel more closely than does Kubrick's film.
(Two of the more noticeable omissions from the new adaptation are the "I am Spartacus!" scene and the reunion of Spartacus and his wife after the
battle.) The miniseries is shown as a story a woman narrates to her son, who are later revealed to be Spartacus' wife and son.
A notable piece of dramatic license has Spartacus' son born
exactly at the moment Spartacus dies in battle.
As Marcus Crassus and Pompey Magnus are being proclaimed co-consuls, the announcer
calls Rome an Empire, when it was still a Republic at the time.
However, in  contemporary Latin, the meaning of “Imperium“,
empire, just meant area where one exercises power.
The film explores themes of gladiator, rome, italy,
roman empire, gladiator fight, slavery.
The tone is emotional.